<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Daniel]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Daniel]]></description>
        <link>http://daniel.swidnikk.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 04:20:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://daniel.swidnikk.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 04:20:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aquisition: BlackBerry Is Buying File Security And DRM Startup WatchDox for up to $150M]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/4564537db425a152daea7b438b6d1874/noop?input=https%3A%2F%2Ftctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fscreen-shot-2015-04-21-at-12-30-04.png%26h%3D384%26crop%3D1"><h1>Aquisition: BlackBerry Is Buying File Security And DRM Startup WatchDox for up to $150M</h1><p>Canadian handset maker BlackBerry has been on a mission to turn around its beleaguered handset business by focusing more on software, and it looks like it has taken a significant step in that direction, specifically around file security and DRM.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/21/blackberry-watchdox/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">02344b7c-9a52-437d-866f-a57c658fda57</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 19:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Macmillan Buys Late Nite Labs To Help Bring Virtual Science Labs To Higher Ed]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Acquisition of a product well built.</p>,<article><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/225ee03465f335dfc317597dfa33823a65984abe"><h1>Macmillan Buys Late Nite Labs To Help Bring Virtual Science Labs To Higher Ed</h1><p>Another day, another acquisition in the education technology market. As the old, familiar names in publishing and education move to get in line with the digital revolution, they&apos;re finding plenty of opportunities amidst today&apos;s growing roster of young EdTech startups.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/macmillan-buys-late-nite-labs-to-help-bring-virtual-science-labs-to-higher-ed/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7f9026af-bf48-47fa-a033-712f1a044ea0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 19:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abe’s Market Acquired!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abe’s Market Acquired!</h1>,<p>Abe's Market was one of the early market places for natural and organic products. It was in production at <a href="http://www.abesmarket.com/">http://www.abesmarket.com</a> and as architect and development lead, I designed an early cloud solution on Amazon Web Services and CentOS for high availability and scalability. I also deployed a uniform development environment, issue management system, SVN, and led Magento development.</p>,<article><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b737e5cb-2f21-4272-91e5-8f84b1c89a74.jpg"><p>Abe&apos;s Market was an early online marketplace for natural and organic products that I architected way back in 2009... </p></article>,<p>I check in on past projects from time to time and have been delighted to witness the success of Abe’s Market. This week <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/l1riddrq2qpn0nm/abesmarket-acquisition.pdf?dl=0">their brand was acquired</a>. I recall admiring the founders’ shift and focus on what they believed in after many years at a large fortune 500 healthcare company, that some might have confused as industrial chemical company ^_^</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://daniel.swidnikk.com/abes-market-acquired/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b98971bc-6c34-4a37-a97d-e9b584244f60</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 19:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tools of my Trade]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/46e7a2c3-03bd-4bb1-b80b-63dbe48bfa23.jpg">,<h1>Tools of my Trade</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/09d1b829-e5a5-4187-9bb9-528981454ff9.png">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/c8e1b0e40247ef69342550d3ca911db2be6b155b.png">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/eebb149c5b904c68971eb6191c27b92d7cd3f60e.png">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/c7fd8a0a9f9f0e424f6f89bd3b862877/croprotate.png?cropheight=178&cropwidth=225&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F07fd72d6-18ae-4956-9eea-326b67410cc8.png&x=0&y=23">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/663f5291-dd35-41e9-8543-57be013ed6f7.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/0a170e6f-a7e8-47a2-8942-6fd5eb8441f6.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/52dbe559-10f5-44b8-b3b5-7e5a6e87d268.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c9a70a6b-46a3-4507-bc71-59611dd2f312.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4c7ca934-83aa-4046-afc8-d604c916c176.png">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/c3b01c088da33a0d3f37e28c6cb36ca2/croprotate.png?cropheight=208&cropwidth=234&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F3bcdeb62-9fe6-4cac-9198-76e097098886.png&x=4&y=0">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8049b2b5-d45a-40ea-bbaa-42e3a7146012.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/22afd6ee-8530-4b3b-862e-8587e0b4e7ec.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/27832914-eeb7-4277-b05a-80160a72cba4.png">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/cb31a487ce57e00d53c4a12bdbe70597/croprotate.png?cropheight=82&cropwidth=259&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F7d3dc481-e225-4469-883b-450b9df350ab.png&x=3&y=0">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/54627eccb7ea6b6be84ed322ae5b068e/croprotate.png?cropheight=225&cropwidth=167&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F2b66c147-cf83-4139-8698-1af6a7c3314e.png&x=25&y=0">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/97d69ee749780f64092dfc72f0b645ac/croprotate.png?cropheight=125&cropwidth=390&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fe71e2bf0-253b-45e1-b79c-ccd04646d497.png&x=0&y=2">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f42e8e26-9f19-4f8d-8461-cd3ed167002b.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b42bf0ab-f97b-4ee6-a861-bc22ab25910a.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/923a47d1-a688-49e4-91d2-6a4ca71ef34b.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/7671c0f5-9c1c-4c1f-8454-044bbce6b518.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4f8eefd9-928a-428f-94fd-f4ac1f6e0543.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ab117344-8a60-4409-a785-dbda66786ba9.png">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/5e0fe20ead27dae5e26c6db7063d1576/croprotate.png?cropheight=227&cropwidth=279&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F9b1f68d9-11ca-434f-9284-b6897d1e8c6e.png&x=0&y=34">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8627e5b4-eb08-451d-bacb-bf3205dc6ba5.png">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/752804a37b641772e910d2ead1fbddbd/croprotate.png?cropheight=113&cropwidth=444&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc0cf3d4c-b912-47b1-b731-decdfab39d1f.png&x=1&y=0">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a4505fec-42b5-43a4-b2d7-d5e53663a6e8.png">,<ul><li>Intercom</li><li>InvisionApp</li><li>Sketch</li><li>Slack</li><li>Trello</li><li>Zapier</li><li>Inbox</li><li>Twilight</li><li>Google Photos</li><li>BufferApp</li><li>Mural</li><li>Pocket</li><li>Soundcloud</li><li>AdBlockPro</li><li>TunnelBear</li><li>The Grid</li><li>GSuite</li><li>Github</li><li>CircleCi</li><li>Mint</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://daniel.swidnikk.com/tools-i-love/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6d330e92-9baf-43e2-9532-a3d12d8cb944</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 12:59:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Contact</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJw9j1sKwjAURLdSsoAkUpUqplIVQRDFF-KXtL23acSYkkSrrt63n2eYGWZ6qrCpxsDZXJDS-8p1GQOTOyqNkUekudGsMFY7BgxZY5xMqsV0VVyXSfOu57PFZn3YzaOdC9tJzvX-coRkeNtew_Z4MNpm4b7KOI9qdlFYv2r6qDMEQBDenpEEtQJfCtLqcBKUqGTpBYn4E96zMmMBrSBP1qmV6vSz_IVvnpN4alJQJ0kp7bHPqfgBnAZKMQ" height="800"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJw9j1sKwjAURLdSsoAkUpUqplIVQRDFF-KXtL23acSYkkSrrt63n2eYGWZ6qrCpxsDZXJDS-8p1GQOTOyqNkUekudGsMFY7BgxZY5xMqsV0VVyXSfOu57PFZn3YzaOdC9tJzvX-coRkeNtew_Z4MNpm4b7KOI9qdlFYv2r6qDMEQBDenpEEtQJfCtLqcBKUqGTpBYn4E96zMmMBrSBP1qmV6vSz_IVvnpN4alJQJ0kp7bHPqfgBnAZKMQ</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">43489015-9a7a-4760-a4e4-2399beb5c1a4</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 08:36:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Portfolio</h1>,<h2>A sampling of my works</h2>,<p>I make this and that with these and those. Because it…</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://daniel.swidnikk.com/portfolio/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a49ef23e-e7f3-43f9-90fb-47660d90b078</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 20:31:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swid System]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Swid System</h1>,<h2>10 steps to thoroughbred your product and team into a romping riding success.</h2>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f3b8ed80-68d7-4ea6-b028-d2d8cb5bc821.jpg">,<h3>Step 1. Map Relationships</h3>,<p>Activities I engage in for any new project, company, or team include a considerable amount of observation, listening, and mapping.</p>,<p>At a high level, I seek to understand the business model. I map out the relationships of the business so that I understand our value proposition, strategic partnerships and key activities that contribute towards the delivery of value. Next I focus on our customer relationships, and strategic partnerships. The key activities that help us deliver value. I notice weaknesses and possible areas to improve.</p>,<h3>Step 2. Know my People</h3>,<p>At every opportunity I expand the relationship and capacity of the team I am working with by beginning to intentionally form relationships. I ask questions about process, experience, and especially key challenges. I ask what would be the biggest contribution to them right now, I write that down. I also spend time on what I call “the extraordinary in the ordinary.” These are noticing the small ordinary things that interest people and light them up, where do they find joy in their lives? Maybe is photography or board games. I take a genuine interest and learn from them on this topic. Lastly, I notice where the strong relationships already lie. For example, if the marketing manager is friends with the CEO or maybe she has many differences with the engineering manager and its strictly business. I see opportunity there and think about opportunities for them to get to know one another.</p>,<p>Education, I look for what collaboration methods a team is comfortable with and create a strategy for ongoing education if there are holes.</p>,<p>Team self assessment. At some time or another, I learned a very simple exercise for a team to self assess their capabilities. This can help with hiring, career growth, and team building. I ask others what their core competencies are and then I make a pie out of that. I take the sum total of all of these and have people rate themselves from 0 to 4. Next, I combine all of these together, with shaded regions being the darkest. From this, the team can see where they lack expertise, and can decide how best to fill it.</p>,<p>Lastly, I want to say that its important to understand what the general mood is. Are people feeling overwhelmed because there is so much to do? Is there not enough motivation and people are slacking? Are people not talking because of lack of trust and safety? Openness cannot be taken for granted and must be bidirectional.</p>,<h3>Step 3. Outcomes, Assumptions, and Success Metrics</h3>,<p>I frame the challenge to accomplish in terms of outcomes, assumptions, and success metrics. Outcomes are a way of standing in the future and looking back at the past. What was accomplished, what was the outcome and the impact on the business or customers? We reduced churn by 20%, increased signups, customers are happy. I’ve learned that outcomes are much more valuable than features. Features must support outcomes and so when I notice the outcomes and validate those, then it becomes much easier to communicate with others and make smart decisions around features. The last piece is to be explicit and understand what will tell us we’re on the right path, this must be specific that we can measure.</p>,<h3>Step 4. Belief Statements</h3>,<p>I like to list these outcomes in terms of belief statements. We believe we will achieve this outcome, with this feature and we will be successful when this metric changes.</p>,<h3>Step 5. Just Enough Process</h3>,<p>How our team delivers value is very important. For a technical team there are foundations that help to remove interruptions and allow team members to focus on getting work done and collaborating. Constant interruptions will ruin this. So I notice and help to externalize this from our backlog. Next I emphasize the big picture and collaboration with user story mapping. Often I’ll start the mapping myself and then use the map to tell a story. This naturally leads others to be curious of process and want to learn more.</p>,<h3>Step 6. Customers</h3>,<p>In most situations, I find teams are distant from customers. There is often natural synergy in customer success so putting team members regularly in touch with success reps help teams to build empathy and curiosity about the customers. Would they like what I’m building? Will they care? Will they find value in this? I find it much easier to build products when team members truly care about the people they creating for.</p>,<p>When writing stories, I’ve found the Jobs To Be Done framework to be extremely valuable and gives teams much more flexibility to capture the context for a specific story. The template is “When I am [context], and I want [outcome], so that [result]”. A good example, would be, When I’m running late can’t miss that important meeting and worried that I won’t find parking near where I’m meeting, and I quickly want to compare options for uber and lyft versus driving so that I decide how to travel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://daniel.swidnikk.com/swid-system/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">14e17ccd-3bf9-40de-8592-d7ff955d9fda</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 14:36:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Case Studies</h1>,<p>On this page, I have collected several of the projects that have stood out and I take a closer in depth look at some of the lessons I learned. </p>]]></description>
            <link>http://daniel.swidnikk.com/case-studies/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1da3c167-8b80-4ae3-b608-76576871e120</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 04:20:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>